## Xiaoxiao Gan

xiaoxiaog22@vt.edu

# Objective

My name is Xiaoxiao Gan, I am a second year PhD student in Virginia Tech. I am interested in software engineering, particularly in software testing, code quality improvement, software maintenance and evolution. My major is Computer Science and my research area of interest is software engineering. More specifically, I am interested in software testing, code quality improvement, software maintenance and evolution. My goal is to strengthen my skills for research in the field of software engineering to explore different methodologies to support developers' daily work. After graduation, I am planning to come back to China for a teaching or research position in southern China universities such as Guangxi University.

#### Education

Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University — Ph.D in

2022.05 - Present

Computer Science, Blacksburg, VA, US

Relevant coursework: Independent Study, Software Engineering, Research Seminar, Information visualization, Research Methods in Computer Science, Advanced Machine Learning, Graduate Assistant Workshop

Florida State University - M.S in Computer Science, Tallahassee, FL, US

2016.08 - 2018.12

GPA - 3.83 out of 4

Relevant coursework: Software Engineering, Database Systems, Concurrent, Parallel and Distributed Programming, Theory of Automata, Data and Computer Communications

Guangxi University — B.S in Network Engineering, Nanning, Guangxi, China

2011.09 - 2015.07

GPA - 85.16 out of 100

Relevant coursework: Programming Design Basis, Data Structure,
Object-oriented Programming, Advanced Mathematics, Linear Algebra,
Methodology of Computer science and Tech, Principle of Computer
Composition

### **Publications**

I have no publications.

# Experience

Teaching Assistant — Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University (Virginia Tech)

2022.08 - 2024.05

Duties included: Teaching assistant for class Software engineering and class intermediate software engineering. Held weekly office hours to help students with homework and project assignments. Graded homework, projects, midterms, and finals.

Software Engineer— Diverse Computing Inc.

2019.02 - 2022.01

Duties included: Design, develop, test and maintain software web applications for the Law Enforcement/Public Safety industry to process criminal data across states.

Junior System Analyst (Intern)— Diverse Computing Inc.

2018.05 - 2018.12

Duties included: Analyzed different projects requirements, created different projects which served as a communication interface with various governmental database systems with company software.

Teaching Assistant – Florida State University

2017.08 - 2018.05

Duties included: Teaching assistant for class data structure and algorithm and class Introduction of Web Application. Held weekly office hours to help students with homework and project assignments. Graded homework, projects, midterms, and finals.